Guide to the American Association of Family and Consumer Sciences records, 1899-2008.
American Association of Family and Consumer Sciences records,
- Series II. Administration
  - Projects and Programs
    - International Family Planning Project
      - Reports
        - Annual report, AID/dspe-G-0010 (2 copies), 1979-10-1980-09 (Box 260)
        - Semi-annual reports, grant no. AID/dspe-G-0010 (2 copies), 1978-10-1979-09 (Box 260)
        - Semi-annual report, grant no. AID/dspe-G-0010 (2 copies), 1979-04-1979-09 (Box 260)
        - Semi-annual report, grant no. AID/dspe-G-0010, 1980-04-1980-09 (Box 260)
        - Internal evaluation of Family Planning Through Home Economics, 1977-1979 (Box 260)
        - Phase-out plans, grant no. AID/dspe-G-0010 (Box 260)
        - Final report, grant no. AID/dspe-G-0010 (2 copies) (Box 260)
      - Publications and educational materials
        - Family Planning and Population Education in Home Economics - a Sourcebook for Teachers (4 copies), 1977 (Box 83)
        - Participant Follow-Up Survey, Barbara A. Holt (3 copies) (Box 83)
        - Home Economics/Family Planning materials (Spanish) (3 sets) (Box 83)
        - International Dimensions of the AHEA (2 copies) (Box 83)
        - Handbook of Teaching Strategies and Techniques for Use in Implementing Lessons Relating to Family Planning, Population Education, and Quality of Life (AHEA), October 1974 (Box 83)
        - Increasing Family Planning Support Through Extension Home Economists (2 copies) (Box 83)
        - Home Economics/Family Planning materials (English) (3 sets) (Box 83)
        - Nutrition and Family Planning, 1976 (2 copies) (Box 83)
        - Family planning slide kits (Box 2)
        - Taiwan workshop, photograph albums (2) (Box 449)
        - Working with Villagers
          - Originals of Arabic Trainers' Manuals, 3 folders (Box 83)
          - Originals of Arabic Media resource books, 3 folders (Box 83)
          - Originals of Arabic Prototype lessons, 3 folders (Box 83)
          - Originals of French Trainers Manuals, 3 folders (Box 83)
          - Originals of French Media resource book (Box 83)
          - Originals of French Media resource books, 2 folders (Box 174)
          - Originals of French Prototype lessons, 3 folders (Box 174)
          - Originals of Spanish Trainers Manuals, 7 folders (Box 174)
          - Originals of Spanish Media resource books, 5 folders (Box 174)
          - Originals of Spanish Prototype lessons, 4 folders (Box 174)
          - English Trainers Manuals, 3 folders (Box 174)
          - English Media resource books, 2 folders (Box 174)
          - English Prototype lessons, 3 folders (Box 174)
        - Project promotional ideas and activities (Box 174)
        - Guide to use-Home Economics and Family Planning slide-cassette kit (Box 174)
        - Partners in Change script (English) (Box 174)
        - Partners in Change script (Spanish) (Box 174)
        - International Federation for Home Economics membership letter, January 1981 (Box 174)
        - A Force for Families (2 copies) (Box 174)
        - Integrated Home Economics Programs: An International Force for Families brochure (Box 174)
        - Enriching Family Life, Strengthening the Nation (Box 174)
        - "The Time is Now" brochure (Box 174)
        - IFPP/AHEA publications brochure (Box 174)
        - IFPP/AHEA publications brochure (Spanish) (Box 174)
        - "Working with Villagers" kit description (2 copies) (Box 174)
        - Resource Catalog-Family Planning and Population Education in Home Economics, 1975, 1977; 2 folders (Box 157)
        - Programas Integrados de Economía Doméstica: Una Fuerza Internacional para la Familia (Box 157)
        - Les Programmes Integres d'Economie Familiale: Une Force Internationale au Service des Familles (Box 157)
        - Integrated Home Economics Programs: An International Force for Families (Box 157)
        - Reprints, Journal of Home Economics, regarding: IFPP and family planning (Box 157)
        - International Update (AHEA International Section), 1980-1981; 2 folders (Box 157)
        - The Link (AHEA-IFPP) (v.1-5), 1975-1980; 6 folders (Box 157)
        - Photographs, The Link v.5 n.1, September 1979 (Box 157)
        - The Link, v.5 [sic][6] n.1-4, 1980-1981 (Box 157)
        - El Eslabon [The Link-Spanish version], v.4 n.4, v.5 n.2-4, v.5 [sic][6] n.1-2, 1979-1980 (Box 157)
        - Handbook of Home Economics Lessons Incorporating Family Planning, Population Education, and Quality of Life-working draft (2 copies), October 1974 (Box 157)
        - Partners in Change slides, script, cassette tape, and guide for use (Box 157)
        - Womens' [sic] Roles and Education: Changing Traditions in Population Planning (Box 157)
        - Guidelines for Forming Home Economics Associations (Box 157)
        - Sierra Leone family planning education leaflets (Box 157)
        - Home Economics and Family Planning-Resource Papers for Curriculum Development (Box 157)
        - Village Visuals: Making and Using Visual Aids with Villagers (Box 157)
        - Family Planning in Home Economics (Box 157)
        - Integrating Family Planning and Home Economics-Resource Handbook (Parts 1 and 2), 2 folders (Box 157)
        - Integracíon de Planificacíon Familiar y Educacíon para el Hogar-Libro de Recursos (1 Parte, 2 Parte), 2 folders (Box 157)
        - Homemaking Handbook for Village Workers in Many Countries (2 copies) (Box 157)
        - Report of a Country Survey on Some Aspects of Family Planning in Rural Jamaica, by Novlet C. Jones, IFPP-AHEA & Jamaican HEA, 1980-06 (Box 157)
        - Biology and family planning posters (Mapcase-folder 4)
        - "Babies Come to Meh Husband and Me like Showers from Heaven" [slides] (Box 175)
        - "The Integration of Population Education and Family Planning in a Marriage and Family Course" [slides] (Box 175)
        - "Population Education and Family Planning Education in a Marriage and Family Course" [slides] (Box 175)
        - "More Children, More Poverty" [slides] (Box 175)
        - Slideshow scripts (Box 175)
        - "Making Vegetable Puppets" [contains photograph] (Box 175)
        - Puppets and Population [book] (Box 175)
        - Hand puppet (Box 175)
        - Family Planning as an Integral Part of a Clothing Unit (brochure and posters) (Box 175)
      - Photographs and slides
        - Philippines-International Federation for Home Economics, 1980 (Box 2)
        - Asian Region Workshop (Box 2)
        - History of Project (Box 2)
        - El Salvador (Box 2)
        - Ghana (Box 2)
        - Jamaica (Box 2)
        - Korea (Box 2)
        - Liberia (Box 2)
        - Nepal (Box 2)
        - Pakistan (Box 2)
        - Panama (Box 2)
        - Philippines (Box 2)
        - Sierra Leone (Box 2)
        - Taiwan I (Box 2)
        - Taiwan II (Box 2)
        - Thailand (Box 2)
        - Turkey (Box 2)
        - Clark College (Box 2)
        - IPPF (Box 2)
        - Margaret Manning (Box 2)
        - Seminar-University Pentanian (Box 2)
        - Untitled (Box 2)
        - Miscellaneous (Box 2)
        - Family Planning slide kits (Box 2)
        - International Family Planning Institute, Georgia (photograph album), 1973 (Box 205)
    - Project 2000
      - Executive Committee materials, 1989-1990; 3 folders (Box 92)
      - National consortium, 1990-1992 (Box 157)
      - Executive Committee, 1989 (Box 157)
      - Reports, correspondence, 1989-1990 (Box 157)
      - Guiding principles, 1989-1991 (Box 157)
      - Correspondence, 1989-1991 (Box 157)
      - Press conference, 1989 (Box 157)
      - Proposal to U.S. Department of Agriculture, 1988 (Box 157)
      - General Information (Box 157)
      - General speakers' correspondence, 1990-1991 (Box 157)
      - Executive Committee meeting minutes, 1990 (Box 66)
      - Summit materials, 1990 (Box 66)
      - Model programs, forms (Box 66)
      - Resources, papers presented (Box 66)
      - Plenary worksheets (Box 66)
      - Papers on black male youth, circa 1990 (Box 66)
      - Building Minority Participation in Home Economics - A Time for Action, meeting materials (2 copies), September 1990; 4 folders (Box 66)
    - Project HEAP (Home Economics Assistance in Population)
      - Report of 1st year activities, 1983-1984 (Box 66)
      - Project proposal, 1986 (Box 66)
      - Project report, 1987 (Box 66)
      - Population education/family planning five-year plan, 1991-1992 (Box 66)
      - Population Education Advisory Committee, correspondence, 1983-1988; 4 folders (Box 66)
      - Population Education Publication History, 1986-1988 (Box 66)
      - Annual Planning Meeting master packet, AHEA Population Education Committee, November 1987 (Box 66)
      - Proceedings folder: National Briefing on International Development-Implications for Home Economists, AHEA International Section conference, 1988-06 (Box 66)
      - International Federation for Home Economics Congress, 1988 (Box 66)
      - Population Education Summer Grant, 1988
        - Patience Ado Adow (Box 66)
        - Grace Malindi (Box 66)
        - Amy Kabwe (Box 66)
        - Helen Mchatta (Box 66)
        - Margaret Thuo (Box 66)
      - Mini grant to Harriman/Wilson: Hewlett Foundation, 1987-1988 (Box 66)
      - "Population/Family Planning Content in Extension Home Economics Programs" (grant to OSU), 1987 (Box 66)
      - Invitations to African Home Economists for International Federation for Home Economics Congress (Hewlett grant), 1988 (Box 66)
      - Journal of Home Economics special issue, "World Population": correspondence (Box 66)
      - Journal of Home Economics, Population: Issues and Concerns special issue, Winter 1985 (Box 66)
      - Journal of Home Economics, Value-Added Dimensions, Fall 1987 (Box 66)
      - Teen Choices: Books, Babies, or Babies and Books, AHEA; Education Week article on publication, August 1987 (Box 66)
      - Educating Adolescents about AIDS (Box 66)
      - Family Life Education Document, draft materials, CFF-AHEA, Hewlett Foundation grant (Box 66)
      - Illinois Teacher of Home Economics, November/December 1987 (Box 66)
      - Population Education Project, news articles (Box 66)
      - Correspondence, Wilma Goppel, United Nations Fund for Population Activities Country Director of Senegal, 1992 (Box 212)
      - Invite list to 10 March 1987 briefing (Box 212)
      - Proposal, 1986 (Box 212)
      - Hewlett Foundation: correspondence, reports, 1985 (Box 212)
      - Proposal, reports, financial information, 1983-1989; 5 folders (Box 212)
      - 2nd annual report, 1985 (Box 177)
      - Proposals, 1983-1984; 2 folders (Box 177)
      - Hewlett-Project HEAP proposal, 1983 (Box 177)
      - Reports (Box 177)
      - Grants, 1983-1984 (Box 177)
      - Hewlett budget, 1984 (Box 177)
      - Correspondence, 1983 (Box 177)
      - Correspondence and reports, 1983 (Box 177)
      - JHE and Action articles (Box 177)
      - Correspondence and proposals, Hewlett Foundation grant (Box 177)
    - Project Home Safe
      - Beyond the Latchkey: Expanding Community Options for School-Age Care, training program manual, 1993; 2 folders (Box 212)
      - What If I'm Home Alone? (Whirlpool Foundation booklet) (Box 212)
      - Quality Criteria for School-Age Child Care Program (Whirlpool Foundation) (Box 212)
      - Developmentally Appropriate Practice in School-Age Child Care Programs (Whirlpool Foundation) (Box 212)
      - Project staff (Box 212)
      - Matching School-Age Child Care With Your Child's Needs, 1991 (Box 212)
      - Project information (Box 177)
      - Correspondence, 1988; 2 folders (Box 177)
      - Correspondence, 1994-1996; 2 folders (Box 177)
      - School-age childcare (Box 177)
      - School-age childcare/latch-key kids (Box 177)
      - Tools for Schools - Contracting for School-Age Child Care, 1993 (Box 177)
    - Project Rural Reach
      - Staff interviews (Box 177)
      - Correspondence, 1984-1985 (Box 177)
      - Annual report to Weyerhauser Foundation, 1985 (Box 212)
      - Generating income, 1983 (Box 212)
      - Proposal, 1984 (Box 212)
      - Annual report (2 copies), 1985 (Box 212)
      - Packard Foundation: correspondence, proposal, 1984 (Box 212)
      - Final report, January 1986 (Box 212)
      - Proposal 1, General Services Foundation, 1985-1986 (Box 212)
      - Weyerhauser Foundation, 1986 (Box 212)
      - Final Report, January 1986 (Box 212)
      - Needmor Fund, 1984-1986 (Box 212)
      - Proposal II, General Services Foundation, 1986-1989 (Box 212)
      - Packard Foundation, proposal and draft work, 1986 (Box 212)
      - David and Lucile Packard Foundation, correspondence, reports, 1985-1987 (Box 212)
      - AHEA Action article regarding: Packard Foundation approval, January 1986 (Box 212)
      - Final Report, September 1986 (Box 212)
      - Final Report, November 1986-December 1988 (Box 212)
      - United Nations Fund for Population Activities grant, Working with Villagers, 1986 (Box 212)
      - Educational materials (not in English) (Box 212)
      - Potomac Chapter links grant, Tanzania Home Economics Association (Box 212)
      - Report, workshop, 1987-05 (Box 212)
      - Fieldworkers training schedule (Box 212)
      - Correspondence, information, finances, 1986-1990 (Box 212)
      - International Update: correspondence about articles (Box 212)
      - Financial information
        - Shipping, mailing, etc. (Box 257)
        - Training expenses (Box 257)
        - Checks requests (Box 257)
        - Travel, transport (Box 257)
        - Reports, receipts (Box 257)
        - Supplies (Box 257)
        - Printing, binding, etc. (Box 257)
        - Participant training (Box 257)
        - Books materials (Box 257)
      - Plan of work (Box 257)
      - General information (Box 257)
      - Publicity (Box 257)
      - Interns (Box 257)
      - Workshop education: forms, evaluations, test results, 2 folders (Box 257)
      - Tanzania (Box 257)
      - Working with Villagers resource books (English, Tanzanian) (Box 257)
    - Project Taking Charge
      - Pre-annual meeting training (Box 177)
      - Project description (Box 177)
      - Proposal (Box 177)
      - Brochures and button (Box 177)
      - National Research Council (Box 257)
      - Miscellaneous materials (Box 257)
      - Youth Development resources (Box 257)
      - The Population Council: Families in Focus information kit (Box 257)
      - Curriculum (English and Spanish versions), 10 folders (Box 257)
      - Draft curriculum, 1988 (Box 257)
      - Final report for first grant year, 1988 (Box 257)
      - Incoming correspondence, 1990-1991 (Box 257)
      - Test instruments, versions and reviews, 1987-1989 (Box 257)
      - Final report, 1990 (Box 257)
      - Grant extension proposal, 1990; 2 folders (Box 257)
      - Proposal for 2nd-year funding, 1988 (Box 142)
      - Proposal for continuation funding, 1989 (Box 142)
      - Guidelines for the Notice of Grant Award Office of Adolescent Pregnancy Programs-DHHS, 1992-1993 (Box 142)
      - Curriculum draft revision, sent to Office of Adolescent Pregnancy Programs, 1988 (Box 142)
      - Project news, updates, materials approvals, 1988-1990 (Box 142)
      - News clippings, 1989-1992 (Box 142)
      - Field test site reports, 1992-1993 (Box 142)
      - Proposal for continuation funding, 1991 (Box 142)
      - Press releases (Box 142)
      - Articles for publications/state mail (Box 142)
      - Articles/publicity written by AHEA (Box 142)
      - Training information and trainers' newsletter, 1991-1992 (Box 142)
      - Curriculum, 1990; 5 folders (Box 142)
      - Video correspondence (Box 142)
      - New Strategies: Interactive Videodisc Technology (Box 142)
      - Grant report, Enhancing Project Taking Charge with Interactive Videodisc Technology (Box 142)
      - Project Taking Charge II
        - Final reports, 1995, 1993-1995 (Box 142)
        - Notice of grant award (Box 142)
        - Continuation proposal, 1993 (Box 142)
        - Advisory Committee, 1993-1994 (Box 142)
        - Proposal, 1993-1994 (Box 142)
        - Federal correspondence, 1988 (Box 142)
        - PTC III applications, correspondence, 1994-1995 (Box 142)
        - Copyright, trademark (Box 142)
        - Office of Adolescent Pregnancy Programs approved videotapes: correspondence, listings (Box 142)
        - Curriculum, 1991; 6 folders (Box 142)
        - PTC videotapes, [VHS videotapes] (Box 150)
  - Public Policy
    - Legislative Handbook, 1965 (Box 1)
    - Legislation Handbook, circa 1968 (Box 1)
    - AHEA Handbook on Legislation, correspondence, newsletters, circa 1968 (Box 1)
    - Legislation Handbook, 1970 (Box 1)
    - Leadership Development in Public Affairs-A Legislative Handbook, 1977 (Box 1)
    - Public Affairs Handbook of the AHEA, 1984 (Box 1)
    - Public Affairs Handbook, 1984 (Box 1)
    - Public Policy Manual, AAFCS, 1997 (Box 1)
    - Correspondence, newsletter, handbook, and report, 1959-1966 (Box 1)
    - Education and housing funding, 1948 (Box 1)
    - Legislative activities: Potato Grading, Frozen Food Packers, Consumer Consultants, Food Standards, 1957 (Box 1)
    - Legislative, D. Johnson material, 1959 (Box 1)
    - Legislative actions: School Lunches, 1921, 1944-1947 (Box 1)
    - Legislative actions, 1946 (Box 1)
    - Social security, 1950 (Box 1)
    - Youth Conservation Clearing House, 1950 (Box 1)
    - Legislation, 1960-1961 (Box 1)
    - Legislative-School lunch, etc., circa 1940; 3 folders (Box 1)
    - Bills and statements from members, 1965-1966; 2 folders (Box 1)
    - Cuts in clothing and housing research funds, 1965-1966 (Box 1)
    - Statements on clothing and housing research, 1965 (Box 1)
    - Cutbacks in research in clothing and housing, USDA, 1965 (Box 1)
    - Elimination of clothing and housing research at the USDA, 1965 (Box 1)
    - Statements, 1964-1966 (Box 1)
    - Minutes, circa 1960 (Box 1)
    - Legislation, 1964-1965 (Box 1)
    - Civil rights bill, 1963-1964 (Box 1)
    - AHEA Annual Public Policy Workshop, 1979, 1980; 2 folders (Box 1)
    - Public Affairs correspondence, 1979 (Box 1)
    - Families, legislation, 1975 (Box 1)
    - Cooperative extension services in D.C., S.2105, 1967 (Box 1)
    - Consumer and homemaking education, 1971-1972, 1979 (Box 1)
    - Equal Rights Amendment, 1972 (Box 1)
    - Family Assistance Plan, H.R. 1, 1972 (Box 80)
    - Regulation of FDA, 1969 (Box 80)
    - Metric conversion, S. 2483, 1972 (Box 80)
    - Nutrition and consumer-use research, clothing, textiles, and housing equipment, 1965 (Box 80)
    - Care and labeling of textile products, 1970; 2 folders (Box 80)
    - Public Policy and Legislative Alerts, 1979-1984 (Box 284)
    - AVA/ADA/AHEA regional workshops on legislation
      - Evaluations (Box 80)
      - Expenses (Box 80)
      - General information (Box 80)
      - Individual information on workshops (Box 80)
    - Consumer Interests - AHEA/CIC (Box 80)
    - Food stamp programs and regulations (Box 80)
    - California state legislative activities (Box 80)
    - Mailings to state legislative chairmen (Box 80)
    - Legislative activities of states (Box 80)
    - Information for state legislative chairmen of AHEA (Box 80)
    - Legislative letters (drafts) (Box 80)
    - Procedure for preparing legislation (Box 80)
    - Legislation subject files, 1966-1968; 3 folders (Box 80)
    - Nutrition Education and Training Program, 1978 (Box 80)
    - Legislative newsletters, circa 1960 (Box 80)
    - Washington News, 1962-1968 (Box 80)
    - Legislative and Consumer (CIC) newsletters, correspondence, Washington News, resolutions, 1963-1969; 2 folders (Box 80)
    - Washington Dateline, 1978-1983; 10 folders (Box 80)
    - Washington Dateline, 1983-1984; 2 folders (Box 88)
    - AHEA "Public Affairs Newsletter", 1983-1984 (Box 88)
    - Public Policy Alerts, Hotline, Washington Watch, 1989-1994; 2 folders (Box 88)
    - Federal funding, extension service, circa 1980 (Box 88)
    - Adult vocational education, circa 1980; 2 folders (Box 88)
    - Testimony, 1985 (Box 88)
    - Nutrition and agriculture paper, 1985 (Box 88)
    - Legislation, circa 1980 (Box 88)
    - Legislative file, circa 1970 (Box 88)
    - Consumer and homemaking education legislation, 1985 (Box 88)
    - Consumer and Homemaking Education and the Federal Budget, 1985 (Box 88)
    - Family legislation and Consumer and Homemaking Education funding, 1985; 2 folders (Box 88)
    - U.S. House committee reprints, 1987; 2 folders (Box 88)
    - Legislative file, circa 1980; 2 folders (Box 88)
    - Coalition of Family Organizations, 1985-1988 (Box 88)
    - Coalition of Family Organizations, circa 1980 (Box 88)
    - Coalition of Family Organizations newsletters, 1977-1983; 3 folders (Box 88)
    - Legislation information, COFO Memo, circa 1980 (Box 88)
    - COFO Memo, 1977-1980 (Box 88)
    - Congressional Record-World Home Economics Day, 1988 (Box 88)
    - Government Relations office, 1986 (Box 88)
    - Government Relations Office, circa 1980; 2 folders (Box 88)
    - Government relations, 1987 (Box 88)
    - Update (Office of Government Relations), 1986; 2 folders (Box 88)
    - Legislative updates, policy guide, 1980-1988; 2 folders (Box 88)
    - Policy and Planning Committee, 1985 (Box 88)
    - Public policy resources, 1980-1985 (Box 275)
    - Public Policy Council for Home Economics, 1985-1987 (Box 275)
    - Public Policy office, 1983-1985 (Box 275)
    - Public policy articles, 1981-1983 (Box 275)
    - William Proxmire correspondence, 1985 (Box 275)
    - House testimony on cooperative extension system oversight, K. Green, 1982 (Box 275)
    - Public Policy Council (Box 275)
      - Congressional Insight, 1986 (Box 275)
      - National Health Fraud Conference, 1985 (Box 275)
      - Bork nomination, 1987 (Box 275)
      - News media folder (Box 275)
      - In the National Interest-Higher Education and the Federal Government: The Essential Partnership, National Association of State Universities and Land Grant Colleges (Box 275)
      - NCL Bulletin, 1986 (Box 275)
      - Data collection-education, 1985 (Box 275)
      - Abuse-child/family-newsletters (Box 275)
      - Children-day care (Box 275)
      - Children-TV violence (Box 275)
      - Effective Schools and Even Start Act (Box 275)
      - Even Start-working file, 2 folders (Box 275)
      - Forecast, 1987 (Box 275)
      - Health fraud, 1985 (Box 275)
      - Gramm-Rudman-Hollings law, 1987 (Box 275)
      - Critical issues in Home Economics, 1983 (Box 275)
      - Job Training Partnership Act (Box 275)
      - Rural family stress, 2 folders (Box 275)
      - Massachusetts Home Economics Association newsletter, 1986 (Box 275)
      - Families: Challenges and Responsibilities (Box 275)
      - Joint Council on Food and Agricultural Sciences: proceedings, agenda, 1987 (Box 275)
      - Public Policy workshop, 1985; 2 folders (Box 275)
      - Civil rights restoration, 1987 (Box 275)
      - AHEA funding recommendations for vocational education, FY 1988 (Box 275)
      - State public policy involvement (Box 275)
      - Letters to Congress, FY 1988 (Box 275)
      - American Federation of Teacher conference, 1987 (Box 275)
      - House Education Appropriations Committee, 1987 (Box 275)
      - Minimum wage (Box 275)
      - Photographs (Box 275)
      - Public Policy Forum, 1987 (Box 275)
      - Text book issue, 2 folders (Box 275)
      - AHEA internship/apprentice program (Box 275)
      - A Force for Families (Box 275)
      - Lobbying for Tax-exempt Organizations (Box 275)
      - Public Affairs newsletter, circa 1980 (Box 275)
      - Fax Pax issue paper (Box 275)
      - Families (Box 275)
      - Drop outs (Box 275)
      - Welfare (Box 275)
      - Rural crisis (Box 275)
      - 99th Congress (Box 275)
    - Correspondence file, Kathleen Sheehan, 1990; 3 folders (Box 275)